

Nauman Munawar

Senior Lead Tech



+92.321.6897797



nomi.munawar21@gmail.com



Allama Iqbal Town, Lahore, Pakistan

Summary

Myself full stack developer over 6+ years of experience with PHP-Laravel, CakePHP, Codeigniter, React.js, Vue.js, nuxt.js, Angular.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, jQuery and JavaScript. My back-end expertise: - Experience with all aspects of PHP-Laravel including designing, architect, scaling and hosting. - Experience to build Admin Dashboard (CMS) using Laravel/AngularJS - Good command to build back end with REST APIs for mobile application. - I do code that is based on Object Oriented Programming like I implement DRY(Dont-Repeat-Yourself) and RESTful design model. - I love its simple structure and good interactive mode, an extensive library and great community. My front-end expertise: -Experience with Twitter Bootstrap for responsive web app. - Experience with Chart.js, Node.js, FullCalendar.js -Experience with multi-tier and Event driven development. - Developed rich front-end using AngularJS, JavaScript and ¡Query. - In plus, well aware with Linux, Git/Bitbucket, NgninX, Apache2, MongoDB, MySQL, MVC, AWS, Google APIs (Calendar, Auth, Map), - Familiar with agile software development methodologies.

Skills

WP CLI | WHRPP | Vuejs | NodeJs | MySQL | MongoDB | Laravel | JQuery | JavaScript | Front-End Engineering |

CodeIgniter | Certified Support Specialist | CakePHP | Bootstrap | Backend Development | AWS Lambda | AngularJS | Ajax

Experience

Aug 2021 - Present

Senior Lead Tech

Wise Market, Lahore, Pakistan

Woking as a senior lead tech. Managing team of frontend and backend developers. Also handling UI/UX developers.

Dec 2020 - Aug 2021

Senior Software Developer

Orbit Solutions, Lahore, Pakistan

Working as a senior software engineer for developing and maintaining clients requirements and to make a professionalism in work and working hard to make a structure programming.

May 2017 - Oct 2020

Senior Software Engineer

Sandyapps Tech, Lahore, Pakistan

Working as a software engineer for developing and maintaining clients requirements and to make a professionalism in work and working hard to make a structure programming.

Jun 2016 - Jun 2017

Software Engineer (MVC Developer)

Skylinkx Technology, Lahore, Pakistan

I am software engineer in laravel. It is mvc framework and i am doing multiple projects in laravel with front-end and backend requirements.

Education

2017 🔾

National College of Business Administration & Economics (NCBA&E)

Bachelors in Science , Computer Science Web Engineering, Data-warehouse, Database

CGPA: 3.45/4

Projects

Wise Market

https://wisemkt.com.au/

Wise MKT is multi-vendor ecommerce website. It is developed in Laravel. Wise MKT is an online mobile shopping store launched in Australia that provides mobiles, laptops, and accessories at excellent prices with a warranty. Guided by the Ethos, Wise MKT staff works tirelessly and passionately to bring the best and beautiful smartphones as per user demand and stay up-to-date with the mobile market. We also provide services to buy refurbished mobile phones, unlocked smartphones at the best condition and nominal price.

Poppins Payroll

https://www.poppinspayroll.com

Poppins Payroll provides tax and payroll services for nanny, housekeeper, senior caregivers and anyone else employ in home. I am working as a main lead php developer here.

DIMS LMS

http://www.dimaglobla.com

LMS is made using Laravel MVC User can purchase online courses by paying online payment. - Can view online lectures based on schedule - Can purchase tests and give online tests

Twilio App

• Lambda Functions. • API Getaway. • DynamoDB • Serverless Deployment. • Twilio WhatsApp API. • Node is used for sending and receiving response through API Gateway AWS.

Icyber Shield

Icyber shield is a platform for network and security devices to protect websites and software, in order to make security shield. Created from Scratch using Laravel standard. • Design patterns, made portal system • Worked on security devices API's e.g. F5, Jet nexus, Blackstone One, Splunk, Fortinet, Fortimail, Checkpoint, Cloudflare, Virustotal etc. • Working on more than 35 security devices This platform contains lots of work of APIs. Fully followed MVC pattern for making batter and quality work. • AngularJS • NodeJS • MongoDB as well for the speed and quality of the project. • Structural programming is used in this project. • REST API • Charts (Morris, FLOT, d3) • Maps Integration (Vector Google) • Multiple JS Plugins

Lingsport

http://www.linqsport.com

I have made this project form scratch.. this project is based on social media News feed like comments and latest activities of friends Friend zone Discussions Messages

Languages

English	Urdu
Intermediate	Expert